<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Cianna Bedford-Petersen</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter, Personality, and Mental Health</title>
      <link>/project/twitter-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/twitter-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last decade has seen explosive growth of online social networks, which are now a pervasive part of everyday life for many people. As such, it is important to understand the relationship between social media and mental health. Previous research has documented a variety of relationships between psychological characteristics and online behaviors. For example, it has found that positive and negative emotions are related to self-expression online. Additionally, personality traits are correlated with word use and patterns of “likes” in Facebook and with word use and network structure on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although previous work in this area has been promising, social media studies to date often rely on outward facing behaviors such as public posts or “likes” which are subject to self-monitoring or a public persona. Instead, we will use Twitter friends (the accounts one chooses to follow) as a behavioral measure that is less publicly highlighted on the platform and therefore, less subject to self-monitoring. We will use this behavioral data, as well as, self-reports of personality and mental health characteristics to better understand the relationship between mental health and social media usage. Specifically, we will examine if current mental health predicts which Twitter accounts participants choose to follow. This research will help us better understand how mental health and personality shape people’s online experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Type 1 Diabetes Twitter Communities</title>
      <link>/project/t1d-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/t1d-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last decade has seen explosive growth of online social networks, which are now a pervasive part of everyday life for many people. As such, it is important to understand the relationship between social media and mental health. Previous research has documented a variety of relationships between psychological characteristics and online behaviors. For example, it has found that positive and negative emotions are related to self-expression online. Additionally, personality traits are correlated with word use and patterns of “likes” in Facebook and with word use and network structure on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although previous work in this area has been promising, social media studies to date often rely on outward facing behaviors such as public posts or “likes” which are subject to self-monitoring or a public persona. Instead, we will use Twitter friends (the accounts one chooses to follow) as a behavioral measure that is less publicly highlighted on the platform and therefore, less subject to self-monitoring. We will use this behavioral data, as well as, self-reports of personality and mental health characteristics to better understand the relationship between mental health and social media usage. Specifically, we will examine if current mental health predicts which Twitter accounts participants choose to follow. This research will help us better understand how mental health and personality shape people’s online experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personality Across Situations</title>
      <link>/project/personality-and-situations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/personality-and-situations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previous research has established the principle that situations can affect the expression of personality, though it is not well-understood what specific patterns characterize this change across situations. Here, we explore the possibility of fault lines in personality. A fault line implies that there is a change in personality expression initiated by a transition between two distinct types of situations. 474 University of Oregon undergraduate students completed a questionnaire in which 15 personality tendencies were juxtaposed with each of 41 differing situations. Our findings replicated previous research indicating that Honesty/Propriety yields the least variance between situations while Emotional Stability and Extraversion yield the most variance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal components analysis was used to examine cross-situational inconsistency with four models already present in psychological literature, each implying a distinct fault line. We found that our models of threat vs reward, positive affect vs negative affect, and agency vs no agency were clear sources of cross-situational inconsistency. Finally, to explore cultural differences in personality expression we compared cross-situational inconsistency in Asian and Asian-American participant and Non-Hispanic White participants. Contrary to our prediction, Asian and Asian-American participants had significantly more cross-situational consistency than non-Hispanic White participants for all traits except Emotional Stability. This may be due to a preference for middle responding leading to less apparent variance. These results highlight the importance of incorporating culture into future personality expression research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
